in this video tool we're gonna be going
over how to use interrupts to make
system calls inside of all the next box
alright so let's get to it
firstly let's write the general layout
of a net wide assembler source file
you
what is a system interrupt a system
interrupt is nothing more than a system
call and that basically translates to
making requests from the operating
system and asking it basically to do
something for you in our case we're
going to be asking the operating system
to write a message to this console to
the screen so there are several
different types of system calls and each
of these system calls have a unique
identifier as you can see I did a quick
Google search for Linux system calls and
this was the first resort result that I
got and it displays a pretty good amount
of information on the next system calls
remember one thing to know that is with
system calls you have to have values
stored in registers like the
accumulation register the buffer
register the counter register the data
register and so on and so forth so so to
make a system call for rights we have to
put the value for inside of the ax
register and then over and the BX
register we have to put in the value of
the value 1 which is going to represent
the file that we want to write to in our
case we're going to be writing to file
number 1 which is the Linux standard
output whilst then while the foul number
0 is the next standard inputs the
keyboard and standard output number 3
number 2 is the standard error output so
in this case we're going to pass 1 to DX
register continuing on this counter
register is going to have the address of
the message that we want to display and
the data register is going to just
contain the number of bytes that we want
to write to the screen
so a quick review basically what you're
doing when you're making system calls is
by basically taking numbers into the
register appropriate registers to
satisfy the requirement for that
particular system call W you want to
actually implement
so this Terminator that determinates to
a string and makes it so that we have a
return line and remember for the system
call we need the total number of bytes
that we want to write to the screen and
so to do that we're just going to count
the number of characters inside of this
inside of this string
you
so I counted 26 so that's what I'm going
to put there now let's actually write
the system call and we do that by saying
we have to move the system call that we
want which is going to be 4 if you
remember we want 4 to be our system call
and this is going to be you know the
file the message address and the number
of bytes to write so that's what's going
on
one is standard output while zero is
standard inputs and two is standard
error
now ECX is going to hold the message
address and you do message addresses by
just simply having the name of the
variable that is an alias for them for
the address of the particular variable
next you want to actually put in the
number of bytes to write and we do that
by making use of the message length
and now this is the interrupts
this hands over control to the operating
system and tells it tells it to use all
these informations to make a system call
and so that's it let's go to a console
and compile this program
it says we have an error so let's go
ahead and correct that
problem fixed let's come back
so this is our program let's go ahead
and run our program and it should print
out the message everyone until there we
go
assembly is freaking cool now if you
wanted I can write an additional
function to make use of this program
making use of these instructions so I
don't have to write this every single
time to do that it's pretty simple we
have to create a new stack frame for a
new function
and we're going to call it right
but instead of making references to this
variable we're going to say EVP -8 so R
plus 8 and then here we're going to say
EBP plus 12 this watch my other
tutorials when I talk about the stack
and this will make perfect sense to you
all right so that's it and so now let's
go ahead and change this
we're gonna say push
message length
push message then call right
if we come back and recompile the
program after fixing our problem
and it's still assembly it's freaking
cool all right so join me in the next
tutorial and as always please rate and
subscribe and drop a comment below thank
you